hi everyone this is Joe Brewer and
wanted to give you another update on the
way that I'm thinking about designing a
training program and bioregional
regeneration because a lot of learning
is happening and there are so many
interesting parts so first of all as you
may know I am the capacity cultivator
for the regenerative communities network
which is a global network of bioregional
projects where people in each region
we're already coordinating their own
activities to build regional scale
economies based on environmental or
ecological principles and so one thing
that I'm getting to learn from talking
with people on these different regions
is what's working and what's not working
as they go about their work and there's
some really inspiring projects that that
we can talk more about but also I'm
really thinking about how do we
cultivate an ecosystem of learning
within each bio region and across from
bio region to bio region the thing I
want to share today is how we're
thinking about an in-person immersive
project-based program so we're currently
designing a 30 days certificate program
in bioregional regeneration to be
launched here at Rancho more goat now
we'll teach people the basics of how to
do design at a bio regional scale using
regenerative principles and because it's
immersive and place-based you come here
in practice and permaculture and visit
field sites in the region while you're
learning the program that there's also
an online component but it's done in the
reverse of most webinars webinars are
usually that the majority of the
students are spread out around the world
and the facilitator speaks to them
online and they're all on their
computers what we're doing instead is
creating an immersive in-person
educational experience with different
kinds of experts that we have
relationships to that will dial in and
speak to our students all of whom are
located here at the ranch so we might
have John Fullerton call in and talk to
the students about regenerative finding
for example or Daniel Vall call in and
talk about how to design regenerative
cultures we have a lot of people with
this depth of knowledge and expertise
who would be very happy to share their
knowledge in this way and so we have
this capacity to create an in-person
educational experience with the benefit
of online but in the pedagogy of
immersive project-based learning now one
of the challenges of this is that
normally if you bring a lot of teachers
together to teach students then you have
to pay the teachers and it costs a lot
of money that means that the price of
the program is really high now we don't
want this to be an expensive program we
want it to be an inexpensive program we
want people to feel like they can afford
to pay the tuition and come for a month
and really dedicate themselves and so in
the beginning we won't be able to pay
we'll have an honorary like thank you
for calling in as an expert to teach
with us but if we replicate the
curriculum across three generative
campuses where an increasing number of
bioregional learning centers in
different bioregions offer the same 30
day course and they each have their own
cohort of students doing project-based
immersive learning then they can all
dial in for the same webinar instruction
with the same set of experts and it
grows in size with the number of bio
regions that are involved so thinking in
this way we can help create more
cohesion and shared learning within bio
regions and across bio regions by making
the curriculum open source and freely
available structuring it so that it can
be shared from one bio region to another
and that the things that are in common
are the elements about how do you design
a bio region and that'll include topics
like how do you set up a
multi-stakeholder collaboration how do
you run effective scenarios and do
scenario planning how do you create a
shared agenda about the future based on
the scenarios that you see and how do
you evaluate your progress as you're
moving toward it while also implementing
regenerative economic
principles and putting in place the
metrics and evaluation tools that ensure
that you are indeed being regenerative
so there are these pieces of knowledge
that would be useful in any bioregion at
the same time there's a global context
that we need a shared understanding
about now we have a planetary boundaries
framework developed by the Stockholm
resilience Center now it shows us what
the thresholds are that humanity has
already crossed in the global system
that place our future in jeopardy so
that as we set these region to region
metrics we can move toward global goals
that oppress them and regenerate toward
pulling ourselves back within those
boundaries and stabilizing the planet
and so there's a set of tools like
planetary boundaries or the donut
economic framework that cater a weren't
developed or the economy for the common
good framework that Christian caliber
developed there are a lot of other
metrics like this that our tool sets
that should be standardized so that and
each bioregion people are aware of them
and know how to use them so what we're
doing is designing a thirty-day
bioregional design program with a
standardized curriculum that can be
replicated in place to place so we will
share with the global network and that
we will invite experts to call in and
speak with the students so one of the
benefits of being in the program is
access to these experts another benefit
will be the Learning Center itself in
our case for the first one Rancho Mar go
to northern Costa Rica but eventually a
whole network of them so that people can
go and learn at the Learning Center for
their own region or they can travel to
another region if there isn't one in
their own region and then over time this
becomes a way of accumulating knowledge
and practices that can spread across the
planet so this is a key piece of how
we're designing this curriculum in
something that I've been thinking a lot
about in the last two weeks while doing
my part to help develop it and I just
wanted to share it with all of you today
so if you have any questions or want to
get involved please contact me and let's
talk more and I will share more about
this design and development process as
we continue